Good evening ladies and gentlemen. A
very warm welcome to ICIC Lumbard
General Insurance Company Limited Q4 and
FI 2025 earnings conference call. From
the senior management we have with us
today Mr. Sanjie Mantri MD and CEO of
the company. Mr. Gopal Balchandran CFO
Mr. Girish Nyak Chief Technology and
Health Underwriting and Claims Mr. Sepit
Kurada Chief Corporate Solutions
International Bank assurance Mr. Anand
Singhi, chief retail and government
business. Mr. Gorov Aurora, chief
reinsurance underwriting and claims for
property and casualty. Please note that
any statements comments are made in
today's call that may look like
forward-looking statements are based on
information presently available to the
management and do not constitute any
indication of any future performance as
future involves risk and uncertainties
which could cause results to differ
materially from the current views being
expressed. As a reminder, all
participant lines will be in the
listenon mode and there will be an
opportunity for you to ask questions
after the presentation concludes. Should
you need assistance during the
conference call, please signal an
operator by pressing star then zero on
your touchon phone. I now hand the
conference over to Mr. Sanjie Mantri, MD
and CEO, ICIC Lumbard General Insurance
Limited. Thank you and over to you.
Good evening to each one of you. Thank
you for joining the earning conference
call at ICL Lombard General Insurance
Company Limited for quarter 4 and
financial year 2025.
Let me give you a brief overview of the
trends we observed in the economy as
well as the industry followed by an
overview of the business. Suppose this
our CFO Mr. Gopal Walachandran will
share the financial performance of the
company for the quarter and the year
ended 31st March
2025. The the GDP growth for the quarter
ended December 2024 stood at 6.2% versus
5.6% 6% for the quarter ended September
2024. As per the data released by Moxy,
high frequency indicators like eway
bills, toll collections, diesel
consumption, and GST collections during
quarter 4 of financial year 2025 are all
indicating positive economic conditions.
Further, MOSI has revised the fullear
GDP estimates to 6.5% on Feb 28, 2025
versus 6.4% 4% published on Jan 7,
2025. Let me not dwell on certain
industry trends which can have an impact
on the general insurance industry at
large. As indicated during the last
quarter, the government expenditure
remained flat which impacted the
commercial line segment growth for the
current quarter. However, we have
started seeing an uptick in government
spending towards capital expenditure in
past few months. This may be a positive
for the commercial line of business. For
the auto industry, we had seen a growth
in rural market in Q3 of 2025.
Specifically for two wheeler segment at
12.7% and the tractor segment at
20.1%. As reported by far, however, in
quarter 4, 2025, we have seen a
degrowth of 4.6% for the tractor
segment. This indicates a softer rural
demand. The private car segment grew by
1.1% and the commercial vement vehicle
segment had a degrowth of 3.8% for
quarter 4 financial year
2025 as reported by far which had an
impact on motor insurance growth for
quarter 4 financial year 2025. However,
for the coming year the auto industry is
expected to have mid singledigit growth.
We remain positive for the motor
insurance business with increasing
penetration in the old vehicle
segments. The health segment continues
to be one of the fastest growing
segments and is the largest contributor
to the industry constituting 38.1% of
the GDP mix for financial year 2025.
However, the industry growth in
financial year 2025 was impacted due to
the 1 byN accounting norm and lower
growth in the health segment, health
benefit segment attributable to lower
dispersement by of credit by NBFC's and
MFIs. We believe that the increasing
demand for health protection coupled
with increased medical inflation may
drive doubledigit growth in the health
segment in the coming year.
There were some key economic changes
which were announced during quarter 4
financial year
2025. The budgetary announcement of
income tax relief provided is expected
to result in an additional 1 trillion in
the hands of Indian taxpaying population
thereby leading to a high disposable
income. The second consecutive interest
rate cut tweaking of norms applicable to
NBSC lending coupled with infusion of
liquidity by RBI should also support
credit growth.
These policy changes aim to encourage
spending and investment. They are also
expected to stimulate demand for goods
and services thereby boosting
consumption and preparing demand for
risk protection through insurance
solutions. However, we remain vigilant
on the ongoing geopolitical developments
which may pose risk to both global
growth and the Indian economy. Now, let
me give you a brief give you an update
on the regulatory developments. The
regulatory the authority during
financial year 2025 continued with
various reforms seeking to expand the
market and increase the penetration of
insurance product towards the mission of
insurance for all by 2047.
I would like to mention key circulars
which were introduced in quarter 4 2025
regarding capping the increase in senior
citizens health insurance premium rates
to 10% peranom and introduction of pima
esba facility for health insurance
policies. We believe these regulatory
changes will improve affordability and
create operational ease for policy
holders. Overall, we remain positive
that the GI industry is poised to grow
in the medium to long term given the
favorable economic and regulatory
environment, low penetration and
relatively higher disposable
income. Now coming to the industry
performance for quarter 4 and financial
year
2025, the gross direct premium income
grew by 1.7% and 6.2% for quarter 4 2025
and financial year 2025 respectively.
Excluding the impact of the 1 byN
accounting norm, the GDPI grew by 8.6%
for financial year
2025. Excluding crop and massel, the
GDPI grew by 4.9% and 8% for quarter 4
2025 and financial year 2025
respectively. Speaking on the specific
segments within the industry, the
commercial segment reported a marginal
degrowth of 1.2% 2% and growth of 1.5%
for quarter 4 and financial year 2025.
Within this, the fire segment registered
a degrowth of 1.8% and 5.3% for quarter
4 financial year 2025 and financial year
2025 respectively on account of pricing
pressure excluding the fire segment. The
over overall commercial segment grew by
8 and a half% for financial year 2025.
The motor segment grew by 6.9% for
quarter 4 of financial year 2025 and 8%
for financial year 2025. The growth in
the segment has been lower due to muted
vehicle sales and continued pricing
pressures reflected by high industry
combined
ratio. The health the health segment
grew at 3.7% and 9% for quarter 4 2025
and financial year 2025. Within this
group health grew at 4.5% and 10.6% for
quarter 4 2025 and financial year 2025
respectively and retail health grew at
7.6% and 12.1% in quarter 4 2025 and
financial year 2025 respectively.
Looking at the underlying performance of
the industry, you may recall our
discussion a year back during our
earnings call where we expect we where
we expected some semblance under
underwriting discipline in the market
due to improvement in the industry's
combined ratio during that period.
However, the combined ratio for the
industry has actually worsened to
113.2% for 9 month as against 112.2% 2%
for 9 months financial year 2024. The
combined ratio for the private sector
has worsened to triple 1.21% for 9 month
2025 from 108.3% for 9 month financial
year 2024. The industry worsening was
largely due to motor segment combined
ratio which increased to 123.8% in 9
month financial year 2025 as against
118.2% in 9 month financial year 2024.
Our continued focus on driving
profitable growth helped us to improve
our combined ratio from
103.7% in 9 month financial year 2024 to
102.8% in 9 month financial year 2025
and
103.3% in full financial year 2024 to
102.6% in financial for the financial
year 2025 on N
basis. I will now walk you through the
company performance across key business
segments during quarter 4 and financial
year 2025.
The company's GDPR registered a growth
of 8% for quarter 4 2025 and 11% for
financial year 2025 on N basis. With the
1 byN accounting norm for quarter 4
2025, the company registered a growth of
2.3% is as against the industry growth
of
1.7%. And for financial year 2025, the
company registered a growth of 8.3% as
against industry growth of 6.2%.
Excluding crop and mass health, the
company's growth was 2.2% and
7.7% compared to the industry growth of
4.9% and 8% for quarter 4 2025 and
financial year 2025
respectively. In the commercial line
segment in quarter 4 2025, our growth
was at 2.8% is against the industry
growth of 1.2%. For financial year 2025,
we grew by 2.5
2.1% as against the industry growth of 1
and a half%. Thereby maintaining market
share. This indicates the strength of a
brand relationship and service quality
in an environment where industry face
continued pricing pressure throughout
the year. In the fire segment, we grew
in line with the industry and in marine
cargo engineering and liability lines of
business. We reported growth higher than
the industry leading to market share
accretion.
In motor segment we grew at.1% for
quarter 4 2025 as against the industry
growth of
6.9%. We continue to drive a motor
strategy based on granular portfolio
segmentation and prudent risk selection.
For the financial year 2025 we grew by
11 a 12% as again the industry growth of
8%. Consequently our market share grew
to 10.8% 8% for financial year 2025
versus 10.5% for financial year 2024.
The portfolio mix for private car, two
wheeler and CV stood at 53.4%,
25.4% and 21.2%
respectively. Our continued focus on
multi- channelannel distribution,
underwriting capabilities and efficient
claim settlement and actual practices
helped us in maintaining our leadership
position. Moving to the health segment,
we grew by
22.1% and 19.2% for quarter 4 financial
year 2025 and financial year 2025
respectively. With the one by accounting
lo by 9.7% and 12.6% for quarter 4 2025
and financial year 2025
respectively. Our retail health segment
registered a growth at 47.7% for quarter
4 financial year 2025 with the 1 byN
accounting norm. The growth of quarter 4
2025 was 25.1% as against the industry
growth of
7.6%. For financial year 2025 the
overall growth stood at
38.1% with one by an accounting norm.
The growth for financial year 2025 was
25%. As again the industry growth of
12.1%. As a result, we gained market
share from 3% in financial year 2024 to
3.3% for financial year
2025. The group health employs employee
segment witnessed growth of 24.9% and
18.5% for quarter 4 2025 and financial
year
2025 respectively. A group other
business degree by 5.5% and with the won
by an accounting norm that the degrowth
was 30% for quarter 4
2025 for financial year 2025 group other
business had a muted growth of 5.3% on
account of impact on health business
benefit business through the bankard
channel with the one by accounting norm
this segment showed a degrowth of 10.5%
for the
year we had spoken about various one
team initiatives in an earlier earnings
call. One of the initiatives we had
spoken about was the consolidation of
customerf facing digital assets like
take care helps app website and digital
alliances under one digital to deliver a
superior customer experience and to
drive efficiencies. Some of the digital
outcomes achieved in financial year 2025
include increasing unique customer visit
by 2x on our digital platform. 37%
growth in fresh transactions on our
digital platform. Downloads for our
one-stop solution one take your app
surpassed surpassed 14.9
million. The business done through the
app stood at 9 927.7 million and 2653.2
2 million for quarter 4, financial year
2025 and financial year 2025
respectively. Consequently, our
customerf facing digital asset business
grew by
15.8% constituting 6.6% of our overall
GDP for financial year 2025.
Now I would like to share with you some
initiatives taken by us for improving
the customer experience and driving
efficiencies for
claims. On the motor side, a preferred
partner network service
74.1% of our nonm claims in quarter 4
2025 up from 69.6% in quarter 4 2024.
For financial year 2025, this number
stood at 73.2%. 2% up from 65% in
financial year
2024. Our cloud calling facilities were
used by 89.6% of our motor customers in
quarter 4 financial year 2025 as against
77% in quarter 4 2024. For the full year
this number was at 86% as against 49%
previous year. This resulted in the
reduction of cost to claim ratio by 21%
for the
year.
Our average claim settlement period for
retail lines of business has seen
improvement from 6 days in financial
year 2024 to 5 days in financial year
2025 for motor and for motor and for
five and from 5 days in financial year
2024 to 3 days in financial year 2025
for health. Our is initiative which was
launched in April 2024 offered an
onground claim support to over 90,000
customers across 56 cities and 2,500
hospital network in financial year
2025. A focus on customer experience and
process efficiencies has led to healthy
NPS of 67 and 69 for health and motor
claims respectively for 9 months 2025.
With all the above efforts, we are
pleased to share that the company's
premium growth has been higher by 210
basis points as again the industry
growth. Our focus on driving profitable
opportunities has further resulted in
improvement in the combined ratio from
103.3% in financial year 2024 to 102.6%
in financial year 2025 on N basis. on on
the 1 byN accounting norm the combined
ratio stood at
102.8% leading to a pad growth of
30.7% and then delivering ROE for the
year at 19.1%.
As we enter into the new financial year,
we remain committed to achieving the
desired scale through creation of
positive customer experiences,
leveraging data analytics and a
technology first approach, harnessing a
multi-product multi-distribution
strategy and with a continued focus on
product
innovation with a core philosophy of one
team, we continue to scale up the profit
pools and to drive sustainable growth.
I will now request Gopar to take you
through the financial numbers for the
recently concluded quarter and financial
year. Thanks Ajivie and uh good evening
to each one of you. I will now give you
a brief overview of the financial
performance for the recently concluded
quarter and the financial year. We have
uploaded the results presentation on our
website. You can access it as we walk
you through the performance numbers.
With effect from October 1, 2024,
long-term products are accounted on a 1
byN basis as mandated by the regulator.
Hence, Q4 and FI25 numbers are not
comparable with prior periods. For more
details on the impact, refer to slide
number 15 of our investor presentation
for further details. The gross direct
premium income of the company was at
rupes 268.33 billion in FI25 as against
rupes 247.76 billion in FI24. a growth
of 8.3% as against industry growth of
6.2%. GDP of the company was at 62.11
billion in Q4 FI25 as against 60.73
billion in Q4 FI24. A growth of 2.3% as
against industry growth of
1.7%. On the retail side of the
business, GDP of the motor segment was
at 107.4 billion in FI25 as against
96.34 billion in FI24, registering a
growth of 11.5%.
The advanced premium for the motor
segment was at rupes 37.17 billion at
March 31 2025 as against 36.44 billion
as at December 31 2024. GDP of the
health segment was at rupes 69.5 billion
in FI25 as against 61.71 billion in FI24
registering a growth of 12.6%. Our
agents which includes the point of sale
distribution count was at 1 lak 40,736
as at March 31 2025 up from 1 lakh 40,77
as at December 31 2024. GDP of our
commercial line segment was at 69.95
billion in FI25 as against 68.51 billion
in FI24 registering a growth of 2.1% as
against industry growth of
1.5%. Resultedly our combined ratio
stood at 102.8% 8% for FI25 as against
103.3% for FI24 excluding the impact of
CAT losses of 94 billion in FI25 and
1.37 billion in FI24. The combined ratio
was 102.4% and 102.5% respectively.
Combined ratio for quarter 4 FI25 was
102.5% as against 102.3% in quarter 4
FI24. Our investment assets during the
quarter rose to rupes 535.0 08 billion
as at March 31 2025 up from rupes 515.99
97 billion as at December 31 2024 our
investment leverage net of borrowing was
3.74 times as at March 31 2025 as
against 3.76 times at December 31 2024
investment income was at 42.5 billion in
FI25 as against 36.1 billion in FI24 on
a quarterly basis investment income was
at 8.77 billion in Q4 FI25 as against
9.54 billion in Q4
FI24. Our capital gains net of
impairment on investment assets stood at
rupees 8.02 billion for the full year as
compared to 5.51 billion in the previous
financial year. Capital gains net of
impairment on investment assets stood at
rupees.06 billion in quarter 4 FI25 as
compared to rupees 1.56 billion in
quarter 4 FI24. Our profit before tax
grew by 30% at 33.21 billion in FI25 as
against 25.55 billion in FI24. Whereas
PBT grew by 4.2% at 6.68 billion in
quarter 4 FI25 as against 6.98 billion
rupees in quarter 4 FI24. Consequently,
profit after tax grew by 30.7% at 25.08
08 billion in FI25 as against 19.19
billion in FI24. PAT degrrew by 1.9% to
rupees 5.1 billion in Q4 FI25 as against
5.19 billion in quarter 4 FI24. The
board of directors of the company has
proposed a final dividend of rupees 7
per share for FI25. This payment is
however subject to approval of
shareholders in the ensuing annual
general meeting of the company. The
overall dividend for FI25 including the
proposed final dividend is rupes 12.5
per share. Last year the overall
dividend was rupees 11 per share. Return
on average equity was 19.1% in FI25 as
against 17.2% in FI24. Return on equity
for quarter 4 this year was 14.5 as
against 17.8 in quarter 4 of last year.
Solveny ratio was at 2.69 69 times at
March 31, 2025 as against 2.36 times at
December 31, 2024 continued to be higher
than the regulatory minimum requirement
of 1.5. As I conclude, I would like to
assert that we remain focused on our
strategy of driving profitable growth,
consistent and sustainable value
creation for all our stakeholders while
ensuring that the interest of policy
holders is in the forefront at all
times. I'd like to thank you all for
attending this earnings call and we will
be happy to take any questions that you
may have. Thank you.
Thank you. We will now begin the
question and answer session. Anyone who
wishes to ask a question may press star
and one on your touchstone telephone. If
you wish to remove yourself from the
question queue, you may press star and
two. Participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a question. Ladies
and gentlemen, we'll wait for a moment
while the question queue
assembles. The first question comes on
the line of Pra Jane from Mutal OS
Financial Services Limited. Please go
ahead. Yeah. Hi. Uh a good set of
numbers on especially on the combined
ratio front. Uh just your thoughts on uh
you know how do we see the growth from
here? uh firstly know from a overall BWP
perspective uh given the one by end
impact would continue uh to be there in
one match of next one match of 26 and
second half would see unwinding of uh
the GWP uh and contributing to some part
of growth. So that would be uh the first
question. Uh second question would be on
your combined ratio or whether you would
look at combined ratio further improving
from the one that reported uh in in the
for
FI25 and a little bit on the fire
segment if you could highlight you know
what are the kind of renewals we've seen
in January and also in in the uh in the
April renewals and those would be my
three questions. Thanks.
Okay. Yeah. Thanks. I think uh with
respect to the growth uh even when I was
reading in terms of uh what it is line
by line I had covered but again I I'll
talk about it. Uh motor per se we are
expecting on the new sale miss single
digit. We also going by the numbers as
has been put across by other OEMs as to
what they are seeing. Albeit the base on
the private car in particular is high.
Uh I also spoke about the fact that the
quarter four two wheeler numbers were
the negative which was a bit of a
surprise as well as what we saw in
quarter three and commercial vehicle I
would be more positive overall because
government capex a lot of other
activities which in the last financial
year had remained subdued should get
picked up. So netn net net motor we will
see singledigit to maybe at just about
double digit growth is what our
prediction is and look all of these
things can change real time we'll keep
you updated but that's what our belief
is on the health side pre our own belief
is we will should see double digit
growth uh now health is two components
retail health and as well as the group
health part of it I'm more clearly
talking about the retail health path
which will continue to see far more uh
incremental business in terms of new to
insurance and also there would be
whatever interest rate growth that comes
out in terms of overall this. So we
would remain positive on health and
health with a 38% contribution will not
be surprised if we see that contribution
probably going to a 40% and thereabouts
and becomes the largest and will
continue to be the largest player. The
last but uh not the least in terms of
the commercial line of business uh we've
had a very one of the most difficult
years on commercial line if you see uh
you've never seen a growth of this
nature going to you know low single
digit in last 7 to 8
years clearly it had multiple factors
fire pricing which we spoke about it
however going forward as the and you
spoke about and I'll probably talk about
the other question that you put across
we saw a lot of semblance in the
industry overall on the fire
side and on that basis we do believe and
we do see relatively much better numbers
on fire and with the activity on the
capex which is coming through
engineering line of business should also
do well. So overall commercial we would
like to believe that there should be a
should be back to a double digit kind of
a growth at the industry level. I think
your last question was on the combine on
the combine. All right. So I think Pesh
again if you look at what we have been
saying is uh obviously our performance
will will be in the context of how the
market uh performs. So which is why we
kind of also put that as a part of the
opening transcript as in to say that at
the beginning of the financial year
concluded we had kind of possibly
expected a lot more semblance to pay out
but in reality if you look at I think
the market seems to have gone slightly
more in that sense north. I think
combined ratios have kind of increased
by almost about 100 basis point at an
aggregate level. So obviously we'll wait
for the full year numbers to play out in
terms of what the players report but
obviously we will be at it when it comes
to let's say driving profitable
opportunities. So hence the endeavor
will be obviously to try and see how we
can create lot more efficiencies whether
it is on loss ratios cost etc etc and
obviously select the right portfolio mix
but obviously we will see how the market
direction plays out and in that context
is how we would also want to see our
combined play through but having said
that definitely I think the gap between
us and the industry combined whichever
way you look at it I think obviously we
will be able to kind of do lot more uh
positives to play out and in the
aggregate I think what we have spoken
about is time and again we will look for
trying to see if we can do that
improvement in the return on equity that
we can give to stakeholders uh the range
that we have generally spoken about in
that range of 16 to 18% the endeavor
will be to obviously try and see over
the long term to move towards the 18 to
20 depending on how the market plays out
yeah so I think and also the simple
answer is uh would we like to improve
our combine uh certainly yes uh and as
Gopal mentioned uh we saw a trajectory
when we came in last year where industry
combined had shown an improvement on the
basis of that we felt we will go uh we
also would like to see a similar thing
but the deterioration has happened and
the deteration more so has happened in
terms of motor moving from 118 to 123
for a 9 month combined but so that being
said we will let uh these things play
out and in our mind the single factor
that drives is are we able to generate
the ROE and that's what largely Gopal is
speaking about it uh as far as we as a
you know as an entity is concerned. All
right. Just your thoughts on motor TV
price that will be my last year.
So we always remain hopeful but uh no
news as yet. So uh is the industry
seeking it? Answer is yes. Is it come
through? The answer is
no in that sense. Yeah. Yeah. Okay.
Yeah, thank you so much.
Thanks P.
Thank you. A reminder to all the
participants in the interest of time
please restrict questions to two per
participants. Next question comes from
the line of Sankit God with Aendas Park.
Please go ahead.
Yeah, thank you for the opportunity
Gopal. In the current quarter we seems
to have done little more reinsurance
accepted business because there is a
meaningful difference between GDPI and
GWP in the quarter almost 10%age. So
just wanted to understand the color of
this business and um do you see uh
opportunity in range accepted with price
hikes going up probably you will do the
same kind of a business in in subsequent
year also. uh any any thoughts on those
lines just just want to understand and
and the second question uh Gupal was
that uh uh see see if you if you could
not book capital gains in the current
quarter uh your your yield remained at
6.3 suppose hypothetically market
remains weak largely for fi26 so so is
it fair to say that your 6.3 6.4 4 is
the yield for for uh for for for
probably for the entire FI26 and
therefore we need to look ro from from
that perspective. I just wanted to
understand that a bit from you and
lastly data keeping questions if you can
give retail health loss issue breakup
and motor GWP break up into new and old
which you usually do. Thank you. Yeah,
maybe I think I'll first uh do the data
keeping question first uh which is
something that keeps coming to us every
quarter. Uh so I'm just kind of giving
you the numbers both for Q4 of last year
and Q4 of this year first and then I
will give the numbers for the full year
in terms of the break up between
corporate health and the retail
indemnity numbers. Uh so quarter 4 of
last year corporate health uh loss
ratios were
88.1%. And the retail innity numbers
again for quarter 4 of last year was
64.6%.
Viz this quarter 4 of this year
corporate health is at
97.2%. And retail health broadly the
range that we have spoken about is at
about
64.8%. On a full year basis this number
for corporate health stands at about
93.7. Last year and the current year re
I mean again last year retail indemnity
numbers is
65.4. Full year this number for
corporate health is at 97.6 6 and retail
indemnity is
67.9. So that's the numbers in terms of
the break up between corporate health
and retail health. Now coming to your
point first question on reinsurance
accepted uh one at an aggregate level
obviously if you ask us underwriting
philosophy is to drive profitable growth
whether it is with respect to the gross
direct premium income that we write or
even with respect to let's say the
reinsurances acceptances to the extent
whatever we do. Therefore from a
philosophy standpoint I think we will
stand committed to driving profitable
growth across the revenue streams that
we source. Having said that I think if
you look at at an aggregate level I
think in terms of the roughly the
premium that we would have written of
close to about 28,000 crores or
thereabout the extent of reinsurance in
world will be a single-digit number. Um
so hence to that extent I think a large
part of the opportunities is what we see
clearly even in the domestic market.
Plus at the same time obviously we look
for given the fact that we also have an
office in our IIO uh business we would
want to kind of continue to see how we
can leverage profitable opportunities
even through the IIO business. So that
is how we would kind of play through
whether a particular business comes
through in a quarter or otherwise I
think again as I keep saying our
business is significantly cyclical and
wherever we see opportunities play out
is how you will continue to see the mix
of business between direct RAI etc etc
play out the larger number to look at
will be more on an annual basis that
will be more reflective of where we are
in terms of our approach to writing
domestic and reinsurance involved to
your second point on uh yeah
sorry so so this I was asking this
question predominantly because because
you you will see a better pricing
environment uh in next fiscal year so so
if other segments slow down say motor
slows down a bit because of the weak
auto cycle uh is it fair to say that
this product might be an opportunity uh
approach to to uh to to drive the
overall growth maybe from that
perspective because environment
exactly so your point is absolutely
right that's exactly what I said I think
if you ask us for us both of them are
preferred areas of opportunity. So
therefore to that extent where we see uh
preferable segments for us to be able to
underwrite we will look at both. Will it
suddenly become a very large proportion
of our overall revenue streams at this
point of time? Clearly not. But
obviously we will look at uh the as I
said profitable opportunities between
domestic and the reinsurance inward and
the revenues that we'll eventually
source will be mix of both.
uh on your point on capital gains, I
think uh if you look at u the uh
approach that we have taken in so far as
uh building the investment portfolio is
concerned, I think uh the treasury team
has done a brilliant job uh in terms of
how to kind of balance the mix of asset
classes between equity and the fixed
income portfolio and that's the reason
during this last periods of high
interest rate regime we have been able
to kind of significantly go long and
which is the reason I think even In our
earlier earnings call we have spoken
about of our duration of the book that
still continues to be slightly in excess
of 5.3 years and if you look at the
yield to maturity uh the yield to
maturity of the book also current of
current currently stands at about 7.55%.
And hence uh and which is what is kind
of translating into if you look at our
marktomarket positions on the overall
investment book while on the roughly an
aggregate mark to market gain as on the
balance sheet date of roughly about 1800
uh 18 billion um in terms of the mark to
market unrealized gains is what we have.
So I think the portfolio is well
positioned. The question to ask for is
what happens in case if you see possibly
sustained periods of price competition
or sustained periods of low interest
rate regime. Now all of that I think in
so in in so far as the second part of
let's say periods of low interest rate
sustaining in the next year I think to
that extent I think our duration call
will kind of largely reflect that and of
course incre reinvestment of the
incremental cash flows will get
subjected to getting placed at a lower
interest rate and that will be true for
the entire market. So therefore the
entire market will have to work much
more harder in terms of improving the
pricing and therefore on balance which
is what we keep saying I think the roe
range that we will work which will be
through a combination of driving
underwriting outcomes and return on
investment that will be in the range of
18 to 20%. assuming the market obviously
shows signs of change and also you know
uh sake now I'll just uh give you the uh
you know lay of the land uh if you go
back in time in April uh as we were
finishing our financial year
2024 if you would have told us to guess
the growth rate for commercial line of
business we would have said definitely
it will be in double digits uh if you
would have told us on the banker line of
business which is a big practice we have
again we would have said a decent with
double digit but as transpired in the
course of the year both of these lines
that are relatively difficult here but
again the emphasis that we have as a
multi-line multi product companies are
we agile enough to toggle uh even you
look at the numbers that you see quarter
and quarter in motor we had a
significant gain in quarter 1 and
quarter two and again in quarter three
and quarter
four we have the PSUs which are build of
severe intensity which is not making
much of an economic sense Hence and you
have seen us growing relatively low
while we finished the year overall with
a gain on market share. So what I've
tried to emphasize to all of you is uh
what we see and what comes through there
can be a gap and as an organization we
are expected to maintain that level of
agility to make those shifts happen and
what we predict not necessarily the way
the market will end up behaving. So you
we will have to factor that and again I
come back in light of that the focus
intently for us as an organization boils
down to are we able to generate the you
know uh that is expected by all our
stakeholders.
All right good yeah
please rejoin the queue for
mr. Please rejoin the queue for more
questions.
Thank you.
Next question comes from the line of
Nidesh Jen with Investeech. Please go
ahead.
Uh thanks. Thanks for the opportunity.
So two question. First is on fire
pricing. Are we already seeing signs of
improvement in fire pricing for the
industry?
Yeah, the answer is yes. There is uh uh
some semblance uh but I would like to
put a word of caution because uh we
still have to see a lot more flowing
through. But as things stand in uh first
couple of weeks of April there was uh
definitely much better discipline in the
market.
Sure. Uh secondary can you speak about
ifs impact on uh our profitability or
roe any any rough indication because
some of the other companies are are
disclosing their FRS number uh which is
also quite useful. So if we can also
give some some indication around that.
So, so Gopal will give the indication.
My my only point is you know just to put
things in perspective uh there is an
economic value there's an accounting
value all these nuance changes are
eventually on the accounting part of it
there is obviously an implication in
terms of how positively IFRS can help us
but we as an organization would 100%
commit ours on the economic value not
only goal if you can just talk about
this I think we have actually kind of
spoken this even in past calls so
therefore I think our stance would still
be the same as in to say that uh I think
we will continue to evaluate businesses
more on an economic basis because end of
the day that's what will eventually
translate in terms of what is the
outcome that we are writing from a risk
perspective.
um transitions to IFRS obviously are
accounting changes which we obviously we
will be uh in that sense well prepared
and at this point of time obviously we
are getting most of our work done
internally whether it is in terms of
understanding the impact of change
getting systems geared up so that as and
when there is a clear regulatory
stipulations as what they have currently
indicated so we will be kind of pretty
much ready with whatever it takes to do
the transition but at the same time I
think what I I think we have been
speaking about also is the fact that as
and when we will eventually transition
to IFRS there will be a lot of in that
sense assumptions uh which will have to
be made by market at large. I think it
is important for again various
stakeholders to ensure consistency in
comparison a need for possibly to see if
we can get a lot more alignment with
some of those assumptions that the
market participants use. So I think our
endeavor is in that direction and which
is what we are working with the council
to see how we can possibly play that
role far better at this in the current
times. But obviously internally we are
pretty much well prepared. Uh major
areas of impact I think I have already
called out. So in that sense no specific
incremental areas to call out as a part
of the current uh impact assessment that
we have done. But yes, we are we are
ready and we will roll out whenever we
see the uh regulatory timelines coming
into action.
Okay. And then uh when we speak about
economic perspective, we are talking
more about ROE and not combined ratio.
Right. This is the operator. Yeah.
Because end of the day I think whatever
you write has to kind of translate into
a return to stakeholders through a
combination of what we deliver on
underwriting plus obviously how
effectively are we able to put the cash
flows to use. So hence to that extent is
what we will kind of be largely driving
as an institution.
Thank you sir. Thank you. That's it from
my side. Thanks Nidesh. Thanks Nesh.
Thank you. Next question comes from the
line of Ain Singh with MK Global
Financial Services Limited. Please go
ahead.
Yeah. Hi uh good evening. Thanks for the
opportunity. Just uh couple of
questions. First one is on uh you know
motor TP. uh if I see again uh around
915 odds of reserve releases you had
this fiscal now of course still you have
not touched your FY23 onwards if I see
or yeah now uh the backdrop is that the
price hike is not happening uh do you
see I mean uh the support from reserve
releases to continue to provide you know
the support in terms of your motorpic
system to catch up with you know the uh
claims in place and then on that front
also another question related is that
okay industry has seen a kind of a
despite this EUM coming the overall
non-claim expense going up now do you
see that scope next year if the claims
were to be under pressure opex side
because now the March 26 deadline for um
limits reaching some kind of a you know
uh uh sanity prevailing among the some
extreme or aggressive peers would you
would that lead to your opex further
improving from here because at the end
of the day that's a sort of a relative
market relative phenomena you cannot
outpric yourself in the market so if if
the peers were to improve will that also
be kind of a you know helpful and the
second one on the approve on renewal if
I read correctly India even in Asia the
research capacities and pricing both
have been kind of favorable so in back
in that backdrop does that sort of a
help in terms of your profitability in
these kind of a very influence heavy a
line item like commercialized. Thanks.
Okay. So maybe I will take the second
part first. I think what you observed is
absolutely right. Uh so so hence
obviously that aids us uh which is what
we have been kind of talking through. Uh
I think the more the market gets
sensible in so far as the need for
compliance to the expense of management
guidelines are concerned that kind of
definitely augers well from an overall
market discipline standpoint. So and
therefore and again as you rightly
indicated FI26 is a time period that the
regulator has stipulated within which
companies are expected to tow the line
when it comes to meeting the guidelines
on excess of management. So, so
obviously this is something that uh we
would be definitely kind of closely
watching for but at the same time I'm
sure all of you are also kind of clearly
hearing that even the regulator is
wanting to make sure that as an industry
pretty much everyone in the market kind
of follows the discipline on compliance
to expense of management. So hence uh
the short answer is of course it augers
well in so far as uh favorable market
development is concerned and within that
indeed obviously that's something that
we have always seen when the market gets
far more sensible on underwriting than I
lumbar by virtue of its uh brand
technology service etc etc is obviously
able to kind of command an incremental
market growth uh without compromising on
underwriting outcomes. So, so that's the
response to the second one. To the
response on the third one, I think with
respect to the reinsurance uh renewal
cycle again, I think you all understand
insurance as much as what we do. Uh so
therefore uh so therefore in that sense
uh uh the the renewals are always
through cycles. You will always see
periods of softness and at some points
of time the market starts to get
hardened. Uh I think the key is end of
the day I think if you look at from our
standpoint what we have again
particularly in the commercial lines
where you relatively see higher
proportion of reinsurance we have
continued to stay disciplined on picking
risks which we think are viable from an
from a underwriting perspective uh
depend irrespective of which cycle the
market is currently operating at in
terms of uh the reinsurance renewals.
Now that's what is finding favor if you
were to see which is what put out also
on our investor presentation as in to
say that the quality of the partners
with whom we work clearly is kind of
pretty much there. So obviously we don't
in that sense want to take any
unnecessary credit risk. So we are very
very conscious of making sure that we
work with highquality panel of
reinsurers. So that gives us a lot of
comfort when it comes to getting
capacity and also now to your point on
terms obviously it's again we get start
we get terms which are better than the
market. uh so even this year at least
what we understand relative to the
market I think we have been given the
underwriting performance that we have
exhibited to the reinsurers I think we
believe we have been able to get terms
both on commissions and the cost that we
incur for protecting our net uh to be
possibly better than where the market is
placed at and that will again kind of
aid us in our ability to further uh
dwell on incremental market share so
that's in response to the third question
on reinsurance renewal cycle
to your first point on motor third
party. I think again I I keep saying
this I think the ranges is what we have
spoken about in terms of the motor loss
ratio. Again I will keep saying we have
to look at motor as in the aggregate and
the range that we have spoken about even
in the earlier earnings call uh for the
segment has been between 65 to 67.
Broadly if you look at the loss ratio
outcome that has played out for even the
current year is pretty much within the
range that we have been kind of talking
about. So hence that's how we look at
now what can happen in case if no third
party price increase sustains for one
more year in FI26 obviously that means
we have to do a lot more work to make
sure that we are able to identify better
risk selection and continue to see how
we can drive profitable growth that's
what we will focus on and more
importantly let's say for the market
they will have to work much more harder
particularly for those companies which
have combined with no third party price
increase and a compliance to expense of
management management yes is something
that some of those market participants
will have to work on. So again we
believe again favorably placed in terms
of the opportunity that one sees on uh
motor third party and finally on the
point on reserving I think again our
approach to the actial principles pretty
much stands intact there is absolutely
no change in the way how we have been
kind of reserving for the portfolio in
terms of consistency and that's the
reason even if you would have seen the
reserve redundancy that you would have
seen across key lines we continue to see
one more year of reserve redundancy. So
that reflects the quality of reserving
that we have been able to kind of play
up to. So hence no change in the
acturial thought process.
Thank you. Very clear. Thanks. Thank
you.
Thank you. Next question comes from the
line of Shria Shivani with CLSA. Please
go ahead. Hi, thank you for the
opportunity. I have one question that is
on the expense ratio for the quarter. Um
so the way I understood uh the the
impact of the 1 byN accounting last time
uh the quarters are similar in terms of
what happened in 3Q to 4Q in terms of
the volume growth that you got or uh how
much you have retained then ideally your
expense ratio should have been similar
to what it was in 3Q even the absolute
amount has declined in 4Q uh if if I
don't talk about the ratio even the
absolute amount has declined. So what
has helped us in having much lesser net
commissions at least if if you can help
me understand this is just about the
quarter
again it's like it's like the question
that keeps coming to us in terms of the
third party loss experience on how the
loss ratio movement are happening
between quarters uh I think again I will
kind of keep reiterating I think our our
focus is very clearly is to make sure
that expense plus commissions put
together as a company we are very very
conscious of making sure that we run the
overall operations at a EOM threshold
which is less than 30% and which is what
if you see on a full year basis I think
for us the expense of management number
stands at about
29.5%. Uh so hence I think we're pretty
much committed within a quarter various
factors in terms of business mix in
terms of efficiencies that we always
keep looking for in terms of our own
internal
processes and so there are numerous
factors that go into it. So hence which
is why you keep urging to keep looking
at numbers more on an annual basis
rather than a particular quarter and
more so on an absolute basis I think
again there can be many factors to it.
So for example I mean whenever if there
are periods where I do a lot more of
those investments in that quarter you
will see the cost hitting us uh and and
so on. So a better number to look at
will be more the expense of management
number than anything else. And also
shares I mean since you're and you're
comparing quarter three and quarter four
just to highlight it's the configuration
of business that comes in in quarter
three we have far more new book that
comes in it's a season where you know
the sale of new goes our market share in
motor also grows in a very very
significant way. in January typical Jan
1st also is a reasonably big line on the
commercial side of the business which
can further impact the expense ratio in
a positive manner. So it's more driven
by configuration of what nature of
business you write which creates the
differentiation and that's what and you
know that when these things happen and
you have a quarter where there's a new
coming in it would impact uh us uh in a
far more you know uh Yeah. Okay. Yeah.
The only thing I was getting confused
that if the retention ratios are similar
between 3Q and 4Q then your commission
rates should have been similar ideally
your net commission uh ratios but I get
the part that if you've written more
commercial line in 4Q then obviously
yeah okay thank you thank you
thank you next question comes from the
line of Prahar Sharma with Jeff please
go ahead
Hi, good evening. Uh just wanted to
develop upon Steve's comment on you know
the uh pricing stance by some of the
PSUs or broader market in the uh motor
vehicle business. uh could you just
elaborate on this that uh you know from
what segments of uh general uh GI
operators did you see some bit of an
aggressive stance uh and uh has there
been any change because you know while
we talk about the EOM uh sunset for FI26
uh are the private ones also genuinely
trying to consolidate on pricing and
second just connected to this is uh is
there a possibility or is there a
discussion around the EOM getting pushed
out by a year or so just so that
everybody makes it without too much
disruption. Thank you. So per I think uh
on the PSU aggression uh it's primarily
driven very extensively on the motor
side. Uh will it sustain too early to
comment? There were shades of that
visible in quarter three but quarter
four if you see they have overall
buckled the trend and they have gained
significant market share also in the uh
motor segment. Uh it would be anybody's
guess in terms of what their plan is. Uh
we are pretty ready to face whatever be
the you know trajectory that they have
and uh we'll wait and see how it pans
out. uh we would continue to as I said
in my uh you know with my you know
initial remarks that we would continue
to flock because these things can happen
at multi multiple level uh at with
multiple players sometimes it's private
sector sometimes it's public sector but
we need to stick to our trajectory of
what we want to do uh with respect to
expense of management uh deferment uh
our understanding is that uh what has
got called report was Poland final. Uh
we do believe it will be it will be good
in long term for the industry if there's
a seminars on that count. Uh we are no
one to comment in terms of whether a
dispensation will be given for another
year. But if you ask a personal belief
another year of dispensation will make
them continue the practice as it exists
and will not change anything because
then they can ask another year of
dispensation. So uh that's where we
would be you know
uh that's where we will leave this part
of the conversation at least.
Perfect. Thank you so much. Yeah. Thank
you.
Thank you. Next question comes from the
line of Aditi Jooshi with JP Morgan.
Please go ahead.
Uh yeah uh thank you for taking my
question. Uh just a very simple one.
Sorry I could not uh go through the
presentation with respect to the
investment income was it uh since the
fourth quarter it was uh lower on an
year-on-year basis. I just wanted to
understand is it majorly on account of
interest income or on account of lower
uh realized gains. Yeah, we put that as
a part of the opening script. So largely
it's because of uh I mean the nature of
how we kind of real the nature of how we
run the overall investment book. Uh the
short answer is capital gains. Quarter
for last year capital gains was roughly
about 150 crores plus this year pretty
much our capital gains is as good as a
very very small number of roughly about
6 crores. So that's last that's the
reason why you see uh the overall
investment income for Q4 of this year to
be slightly lower than the Q4 of last
year. But having said that, I think what
has worked well again as I said, I think
the Treasury team has done a great job
in trying to make sure that the
portfolio has got significantly kind of
balanced to make sure that we go long
and hence uh which is why again time and
again we have been giving the yield to
maturity numbers which used to be less
than 7% that number as we speak
currently stands at about 7.55%. So, so
this is for for here to stay and hence
uh at least for quarter 4 the short
answer is capital gains. Yeah. And also
you know something which I must put
across what our treasury team has done
is even over quarter and quarter we have
increased the yield of the book from 7%
to
7.55. So which is a big one in the
tenure also which has gone to 5.34.
uh overall it puts us well in terms of
the current scenario that exists on the
that exist on the you know interest rate
part and also in quarter three it was
more of a tactical call where our
investment team felt that it was much
better to book capital gains in that
quarter versus what would happen in
quarter four uh in hindsight it did work
out for us
okay that's here. Thank you. Thanks.
Thank you. Thank you. Next question
comes from the line of
Nirjnal with UPS securityities. Please
go ahead. Yeah. Hi. Uh so uh my question
is regarding getting to if I only say
how often think about the globe given
you know what we have discussed uh
they're still giving a lot of
uncertainties as you mentioned and the
group could be different than what we
right now you know think about as sorry
to stop you we're not able to hear you
you're not that audible uh is it better
now
yeah maybe if you can just repeat your
question nearest that will help so one
question on the on the group side uh
because given this online will kind of
normalize from October
uh how it is one thing about overall
growth and the preferred areas will have
been helped and obviously motor uh
there's been a lot of comp intensity
which is you know increased especially
from PSU is what I understand so any
comment on overall growth we are
targeting in FI26 that is one and second
is a bookkeeping question on the other
income from the non-operating results it
seems to be very side. Uh so anything on
that?
So maybe I'll take the first one. Uh I
think on the growth side, Nirj uh the
good part is I think if you look at some
of the actions which are being taken
both at both at various governments and
even our own insurance regulator, I
think the efforts have been very very
positive. I think for example the recent
budget did see a lot of a lot of uh uh
people kind of getting a higher
disposable income which kind of augers
well now all of this will start to kind
of play through maybe over the
subsequent uh quarters so that's a very
very positive action which comes from
the government equally I think
regulators are doing their part in terms
of trying to keep relatively the
interest rate of the environment at far
more acceptable levels and the very
recent rate cuts again kind of augers
well in so far as driving uh consumption
retail consumption and in general
driving consumptions are concerned. So,
so there are clearly lot of positive
factors which should aid when it comes
to let's say growth because ours is a
direct reflection of what happens in so
far as economic activities are concerned
and some of these positive actions by
the government and regulators a very
very well coupled with this I think if
you look at side for the next two
quarters in general I think we are very
very positively placed in terms of how
we see the opportunity play out and also
what we kind of responded to the earlier
question on how the initial corporate
renewal cycle has been. I think that
looks again very very promising. Now
that's something that has started off on
a positive note right from the beginning
of the year. So hence even for the rest
of the year one should see that cycle
play through. So overall I think we are
kind of um positively looking at in
terms of how the market should kind of
play out and within that I think what we
have spoken is to try and see how we can
continue to deliver that out performance
with the industry growth numbers is what
we will be kind of penciling in first
two quarters you are absolutely right uh
in Nirj in terms of the impact of one by
will obviously kind of play out so maybe
to that extent industry growth could be
a little subdued but on a full year
basis I think we are very very
optimistic and any uh comment on the
combination guidance if we are changing
or revising uh or giving any new
guidance
I think we are see on the guidance part
we've given a complete perspective if
the industry continues to deteriorate
our own belief would be that uh we are
part of the same pond right so uh you
would see uh overall all challenges but
in our scheme of things if there is
improvement status quo you would see us
probably uh improving more importantly
it's the ROE part of it which we would
focus on and see what kind of returns we
are able to generate and in that we've
always m maintained that we want to see
at least 16 to you know 20% kind of a
range for us as a company being given to
stakeholders
uh so as the booking of the other income
of the nonoperating results usually very
high. Is it something regrouping or if
you can throw some?
Yeah, nothing specific but it is it is
business as usual for us. They will all
be driven by whatever the regulatory
stipulations are. Uh and uh no no
specific changes per se. Oh, thank you.
Thank you ladies and gentlemen. Due to
time constraints, we have reached the
end of question and answer session. I
would now like to hand the conference
over to Mr. Sanjiv Mantri for closing
comments.
I think uh great to connect with all of
you. Uh closure of uh another financial
year and uh some exciting times awaits.
Look forward to interacting with each
one of you uh as and when your time
permits. uh we do believe that general
insurance industry is poised for a
decent year uh going forward and we
would keep in touch and keep you
updated. Thank you so much for joining
in and all the best to each one of you.
Thank you so much.
Thank you on behalf of ICL Lombard
General Insurance Company Limited. That
concludes this conference. Thank you for
joining us. You may now disconnect your
lines.